字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧、日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译:  芒果赛喜庆元旦   火龙果新年快乐
翻译:  MsFool    glida   洗七里
校对:  赛太公觉得冬歇太短
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第十集
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
-杰  -欢迎欢迎
- Hey, Jay. - Welcome!
在杰家过元旦
New Year's Day at Jay's.
我爸正开车过来
My dad was driving in.
经历了上午的挫折后  一切都在好转
Things were looking up after a bad morning.
-乖乖  -真厉害
- Oh! Yeah! - Oh, man!
看看它飞得多高啊
Look how high it goes!
我到时候要试试朝小鸟吐口水
I'm gonna try and spit on a bird.
那哥们是刚坐完下来吗
Did he just get off the ride?
亲爱的  我有点打退堂鼓了
You know, honey, um, I'm getting cold feet.
不然我们还是...
Maybe we should just --
如果你害怕我们就走吧
Well, if you're scared, we should just go.
我很失望  因为在我看来肯定会很爽的
I'm disappointed, 'cause to me, it seemed like a blast.
我的新年新决心是活得更刺激
My resolution to live more dangerously
结果出师不利
was off to a rocky start.
自己去拆我准备的圣诞礼物吧
Help yourself to my Christmas present.
天下最爽的就是在热水浴缸里喝冰鸡尾酒
Nothing like a frozen margarita in a hot tub.
让自然母亲知道她能做的事我们也都能做到
Lets nature know we can do anything she can.
我带走喝
Well, I'll take one to go.
艾丽克斯和我是要来你们的衣橱里
Alex and I are just here to raid your guys' closet
搜刮复古服装而来
for some vintage clothing.
我们要去一个九十年代风格的音乐节
Yeah, we're going to a '90s music festival
叫"当然90音乐节"
called Fo-shizzle-fest.
准备好吃烤猪撑到爆吧
Okay, get ready to pig out!
6到8小时后才能撑到爆
In six to eight hours.
我负责做去年的感恩节晚宴
I did Thanksgiving dinner last year,
结果没做好
and it didn't go well.
小卡把火鸡弄爆炸了
Cam blew up the turkey
吓得山羊撞墙自杀
and made the goat kill itself.
总之今天的元旦大餐我要强势回归
Anyhoo, today is my comeback meal,
我决定一切从简  做烤全猪
and I decided to keep it simple and roast a pig.
你先挖个坑
So, you just dig a hole,
铺一层炭  再盖一层蕉叶
you put down a bed of coals, then a layer of banana leaves,
把猪放进去  再用麻布和锡纸包住
lower the pig, cover it with burlap and tin foil,
然后是见证奇迹的时刻
and -- Bam!
6小时后挖出来
Six hours later, you dig it all up,
放到盘子上  又是见证奇迹的时刻
put it on a platter, and Bam!
晚餐就上桌了
dinner is served.
小伙子们
Guys,
不要以为你们的圣诞是在密苏里过的
just because you spent Christmas in Missouri
我们就把你们忘了
doesn't mean that we forgot about you.
拆礼物吧
Open your presents.
好  我先拆
Oh, okay! I'll go first.
瞧瞧
Uh, let's see.
是电子管家的礼品券
Oh, it's a gift certificate for E-Butler.
是礼宾服务
It's a concierge service.
你可以用它做跑腿  买票之类的杂务
Use it for errands, tickets, things like that.
我的天  我太喜欢了
Oh my God. I love this!
就像住在酒店一样
It's like staying in a hotel,
但我用遥控器时不必戴手套防细菌
but I don't have to wear gloves to use the remote.
好了  到我了到我了
Okay, me next. Me next.
是条围裙  上面还带铃铛
Oh... it's an apron with-with bells on it.
上面还写着"过来卡一下"
And it says, "Cam and get it!"
所以这个不是拼写错误吗
Oh, so that's not a mistake?
我额外加钱定做的
We spent extra cash to get that custom made.
我在梦中想到的好点子
Came to me in a dream.
穿上吧  伙计
Put it on, buddy.
我们照一张你们拿着礼物的照片
Let's, uh-Let's get pictures with you guys and your gifts.
杰  歌洛莉亚  你们也一起来
Jay and Gloria, get in there too.
来吧  亲爱的  咱也去
Come on, honey. Let's go.
-天啊  -我帮你系
- Oh, boy. - I'll tie it.
-不用  -好吧
- No, you won't. - All right.
我就说斯黛拉想杀我
I told you Stella was trying to kill me!
-刚才真是吓死人了  -又没出事
- Well, that was a scare. - Nothing happened.
我知道你想说什么
I know where you're going with this.
这就是为什么我一直追着你
This is why I've been hounding you
要你做遗产规划
about your estate planning.
不  米奇
No, Mitch.
不要朝宇宙释放这种负能量
Don't put that horrible thing out in the universe!
爸  你还没做遗产规划吗
Dad, you still haven't done that?
自从乔出生以来他们都没修订过文件
They haven't updated their paperwork since Joe was born.
老天保佑  但万一他们遇到不测了呢
Uh, God forbid something bad should happen to them.
我们都不知道他们想让谁做乔的监护人
We don't even know who'd they want to raise Joe.
你别吓她了行吗
Will you stop scaring her?
至今我花在种睫毛上面的钱
I spend more money on eyelashes
吹走掉下来的睫毛可以许愿
已经比你们好多人的医保钱都多了
than most of you do on health care.
好吧  我今天就做
Fine, we'll do it today.
开始新一年的方式那么多
What better way to start the new year
但有什么能比准备身后事更"开心"
than by preparing for the worst?
说到还生龙活虎的老爸
Speaking of alive dads,
我爸来啦
there's mine! Oh!
见到你太好了
So good to see you!
一路开车过来顺利吗
How was the drive?
棒极了
Fantastic.
开到佛州塔拉哈西时我的收音机坏了
My radio broke around Tallahassee.
但哪里有比美国公路上的广告牌
But is there a better entertainment source
更有趣的娱乐内容呢
than the billboards of America?
根据广告来看  梅毒又要祸害众生了
Apparently, syphilis is making a comeback.
再说  你还有我陪你解闷呢
Plus, you had me to keep you company.
洛林
Lorraine?
洛林是照顾我长大的保姆
Lorraine was my babysitter growing up.
我第一次春心荡漾的对象也是她
She was also my first crush
我第一次做"那啥梦"  梦见的也是她
and also the star of my first, um... "funny dream."
当年菲尔一见到洛林就调皮捣蛋
Yeah, Lorraine used to bring out the holy terror in Phil.
好像他故意想被洛林打屁股似的
It seemed like he wanted to be spanked by her.
我才没有
No, I did not.
你们在一起多久了
How long has this been going on?
我们今年早些时候做陪审团时重新联系上的
Well, we reconnected earlier this year on jury duty.
三重凶杀案  只有我坚持认为凶手无罪
I was the lone holdout on a triple homicide case.
当被告是无辜的时候你是能感应到的
You can just feel when someone is innocent, you know?
但洛林说如果我改投有罪
But Lorraine said she'd go out to lunch with me
她就陪我吃午饭
if I changed my vote,
所以我们就在一起了
so here we are.
-菲尔  你做梦都没想到  -没"梦"过
- Phil, did-did you ever dream -- - No.
我上次见到你时
Last time I saw you,
你还在我胸口
you came up to here.
好了  克莱尔会带你们从那边去后院
Okay, Claire will take you that way to the back yard.
我会从房子里穿过去
I'll go through the house
这样我们就终于能知道哪条路比较快了
so we can finally know which way's faster.
好了  只要回答几个简单的问题
Okay, just a few simple questions,
你们的遗产规划就做好了
and your estate planning is done.
这是什么
What is this?
我们不用额外准备一笔钱给曼尼上大学
We don't need to put aside money for Manny's college.
钱我早就攒够了
I already took care of it.
曼尼出生的时候  我不想依靠任何人
When Manny was born, I didn't want to rely on anyone,
所以我开始把一部分薪水攒起来
so I started saving money from my paycheck.
最后就把曼尼上大学的钱攒出来了
Eventually, I made enough money for Manny's college,
这样如果有什么不测  他也不会有事
so if anything happens, he'll be okay.
真了不起
That's amazing.
我看银行财务报表的时候怎么没发现
How did I not see this in the bank statements?
我为什么要把我有可能哪天
Why would I put money that I might need
就需要带着跑路的钱存进银行呢
to run away with in the middle of night in the bank?
我把它放在跑路包里
I put it in my disappear bag.
虽然这事很难不往心里去  但是...
It's hard not to take that personally, but, um,
那包在哪
where is this bag?
在...
It's in...in...
-你忘了 -不可能
- You forgot? - No.
我特地编了首歌
That's why I made a song
好帮我想起来它在哪
so that it would always help me remember.
* 我的跑路小包  我的跑路小包 *
* My disappear bag, my disappear bag *
* 我把你安全地藏在... *
* I hid you very safely in the *
我不知道了
I don't know.
失陪一下
One second.
小卡  我们要干嘛
Okay, Cam, what are we --
你冷静点
Okay. Just -- Just be cool.
-冷静一点 -怎么冷静[酷]
- Just be cool. - Be cool?
你刚像个乡村手摇鼓一样叮叮当当穿过花园
You just jangled across the yard like a big country tambourine.
好吧  貌似
All right, well, apparently,
火刚熄灭了  而我没注意到
the fire went out and I didn't notice,
现在这只猪冷得就像待会你家人发现
and now this pig is as cold as your family is gonna be
我又搞砸了一顿饭时的气氛一样冰冷
when they figure out I ruined another meal.
这很糟糕
Okay, this is bad.
我爸不喜欢被猪肉吊胃口
My dad does not like to be pork teased.
也许我们能搞到另一只猪来代替它
Well, maybe we can get a replacement pig.
-你觉得你的礼宾卡好使吗 -什么
- Do you think your concierge thing could help out? - Wha--
但我今天才刚得到它
But I just got it today,
而且卡上写了  "专为米奇服务"
and -- and the card says, "For Mitch stuff."
米奇尔  我的一个新年愿望
Mitchell, one of my resolutions
就是在外面少流眼泪
was to cry less outside the home.
求你帮我度过今天的难关吧
Please help me get through this day. Gosh.
你知道他们只买给我六个小时的服务时间吧
You know they only got me six hours, right?
我知道  谢谢你
I know. Thank you.
好吧
Okay.
感谢您致电电子管家  普里契特先生
Thank you for calling E-Butler, Mr. Pritchett.
我能为您做些什么让您的生活更"电"捷
How may I make your day more E-fficient?
我有一个奇怪的请求
Okay, um, well, this is a weird request.
友情提醒  色情服务双倍收费
Keep in mind, erotic tasks are billed at twice the normal rate.
不是的  我需要你偷偷地给我送一只烤全猪
Uh, no, I-I need you to secretly deliver a whole roasted pig.
很高兴为您服务
With extreme pleasure.
这种请求提醒了我为何投身电子管家服务
Requests like these remind me why I E-buttle.
我认得那个声音
I knew that voice.
是基夫斯
It was Keifth.
我刚搬来这里的时候
When I first moved here,
我不过是个年轻的密苏里乡巴佬
I was just a young Missouri hayseed.
有一天我买了张票去看马戏团
I-I bought a ticket to the circus one day,
所有演出的焦点
and there in the middle of all the action,
就是穿着完美修身燕尾服的马戏团领班基夫斯
in an impeccably pressed tuxedo, was Ringmaster Keifth.
我开始出没于各马戏团酒吧  直到我们相遇
I started hanging out at circus bars until we met.
瞬间就互相吸引了
The attraction was immediate.
他年纪比较大  总是屋里掌控大局的人
He was older, always in command of a room,
确实说得通  毕竟屋子不过就是永久型的帐篷
which makes sense because a room is just a permanent tent.
我们交往了六个月
We dated for six months.
他使我变成了
He transformed me
现在大家熟识的长袖善舞的我
into the sophisticate that we all know today.
然后他突然间消失了
And then, he suddenly disappeared.
没有告别  没有留言
No goodbye. No note.
只留下了地板上的一些花生壳
Just some peanut shells on the floor
那一定是...  从他华丽的黑靴子底掉下来的
that must have...fallen from his glorious black boot.
我在小波利尼西亚找到了一家小餐馆
I found a trattoria in Little Polynesia
可以提供一只多的烤全猪
that can spare a fully roasted pig.
不好意思让您久等了
Sorry for the delay.
才过了一分半
It w-- It was a minute and a half.
您不知道我多惭愧
You can't know my shame.
我会在一小时内把烤猪包裹送达
I'll deliver the porcine parcel within the hour.
好  太棒了  我们等会见
Okay, that -- that is great. I will -- I will see you then.
你怎么了
What is wrong with you?
我的马戏团男友
Okay, my circus boyfriend who left me
半夜丢下我离开的那个  就是他
in the middle of the night -- that was him.
而他马上要来这里了
And now he's coming here?!
我可不想这么开始[摇铃]新年
This is no way to ring in a new year.
钱肯定在这的某个地方
The money has to be here somewhere.
从我们搬过来后的所有东西都在这了
This is all the stuff from when we first moved in together.
我们为什么会有一盒娃娃头
Why do we have a box of doll heads?
我猜你以为家里没闹过鬼
Oh, I guess you think it's a coincidence
只不过是个巧合
that we have never had evil spirits in this house.
这些遗嘱上的问题怎么办
What about these will questions?
如果我们出了事  谁来抚养乔
If something happens to us, who should raise Joe?
不  杰  别说那样的话
No, Jay, don't say that.
你听着
All right, look.
如果需要别人来抚养乔
If someone other than us needs to raise Joe,
我投票给米奇和小卡
I vote Mitch and Cam.
很互补的一对
Nice balance.
米奇有责任感  他有文化
Mitch is, uh, responsible, he knows culture,
小卡基本上就是个玩大学橄榄球的妈妈
and Cam is basically a mom who played college football.
而且  乔和莉莉年纪相仿
Plus, Joe and Lily are close in age.
对  但她是不是有点...
Yeah, but isn't she a little...
直言不讳  你说的没错
Direct? You're not wrong.
感恩节时  她足足花了五分钟说我的鼻子
She did five minutes on my nose at Thanksgiving.
你的鼻子是有点大
I mean, it's a little big,
但要说它大得都有自己的邮编了
but to say that it has its own zip code,
我觉得还是太过分了
that was too much for me.
这是什么
What's this?
别打开  那是
No, that is...
"如果我失踪了或者被发现死了
"If I ever go missing or am found dead,
是我丈夫干的"
it was my husband"?
这是什么玩意
What the hell is this?!
冷静一点
Calm down.
这是我们第一次大吵之后录的
It was when we had our first big fight.
当然  我知道你不会杀我的
Of course I knew that you were not going to kill me.
我只是准备逃跑然后诬陷你
I was just going to run away and frame you.
好奇怪  我们到了这几乎没怎么见到菲尔
Is it weird we've barely seen Phil since we've been here?
这孩子一直都是个流浪者
He was always a wanderer.
这是对天才的诅咒
It's the curse of being a genius.
-菲尔  -我了个特立尼达和多巴哥共和国
- Phil. - Trinidad and Tobago!
你为什么躲着弗兰克
Why are you avoiding Frank?
什么
What?
我
I'm --
好吧  有些事你不知道
Okay, there's something you don't know.
她曾经是你的保姆  你对她有过幻想
She used to be your babysitter, and you had the hots for her.
你怎么知道的
How?
你打算怎么样  亲爱的
What is the plan, honey?
你打算就一直躲着他们吗
Are you just gonna avoid them?
我只是需要一些时间来适应这件事  好吗
I just need a minute to get comfortable with this, okay?
比如  他是不是一直对她有好感
I mean, did he always have a crush on her,
甚至在我妈还在的时候
even when my mom was around?
一个十三岁的少年故意让他保姆
It's one thing for a 13-year-old to position his babysitter
站在打开的冰箱前  好让他欣赏到
in front of an open refrigerator so that he can enjoy
保姆穿着他从兰德尔妈妈那偷来送她的
the backlit contours of her beautiful body in the silk blouse
真丝衬衫的美妙身姿  这是一回事
he stole from Randall's mother.
但如果他爸也做着同样的事呢
But if he was doing the same thing?
先不管你
Uh, moving past your decision
偷兰德尔妈妈的漂亮衣服的事
to steal trophy clothing from Randall's mom,
或许你可以直接找你爸谈
maybe you could just talk to your dad.
你也知道我们家从不谈事
You know we don't talk in my family.
我们即兴而作
We riff.
或者是讲个段子
We do bits.
知道我爸怎么跟我说祖母去世的吗
You know how my dad told me my grandmother died?
用敲门笑话来跟我说
In a knock-knock joke.
去年的菲尔才会这样说
That is last year's Phil talking.
本着活得更刺激的精神
In the spirit of living more dangerously,
你何不感情上冒次险
why don't you take an emotional risk
试着和你爸坦诚相见
and -- and try and have an honest conversation with your father?
还有
Also,
我穿的虽不是兰德尔妈妈的短衫
well, I may not be wearing Randall's mothers blouse,
但我想或许你会想要...
but I thought maybe you'd like...
他已经走了
And he's gone.
我怎么说错了
Uh, da-- how am I saying it wrong?
-他叫基斯  -不
- His name is Keith. - No.
基夫
Keef?
简单得不得了
It couldn't be simpler.
其土夫其斤  基夫斯
K-E-I-F-T-H. Keifth.
夫斯  夫斯
Fth. Fth.
非凡的名字  非凡的人
A remarkable name for a remarkable man.
马戏团领班基本上就是挂个名的职位吧
Isn't ringmaster basically a ceremonial position?
我真想生活在你的幻想世界
Uh, wow. I would love to live in your fantasy world
里面的马戏团能自行运转
where circuses run themselves.
好了  打电话取消
Okay. Call and cancel.
那谁来拯救你的晚餐
Then who's gonna save your dinner?
而且我们并不确定那个服务生就是基夫斯啊
Besides, we don't even know if the concierge is actually Keifth.
我会忘了半夜抛弃我的
I'm gonna forget the velvety baritone
那个柔和男中音吗
that abandoned me in the middle of the night?
还有  他来这里  我会失控
And plus, he walks in here, I lose it,
我不想莉莉看到那场面
I don't want Lily to see that.
她不在
Oh, she's not here.
她要去朋友家过夜  已经走夫斯
She has that sleepover, and she already leffffth.
都不说再见的吗
Without saying goodbye?
然后我突然想到
Then it hit me.
让小卡见那个抛弃他的
It could be therapeutic for Cam
名字滑稽的马戏团人士可能对他有好处
to see this ridiculously named circus person who deserted him
因为那件事可能就是他
because that incident could be the very root
那么害怕被抛弃情结的根源
of his pretty intense abandonment issues...
这事决不能说不折腾人
which are not unchallenging.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
去洗手间
To the bathroom.
祝你一生平安
Well, have a nice life.
让菲尔和克莱尔照顾乔怎么样
What about Phil and Claire to take care of Joe?
我不知道  菲尔不是有点傻吗
I don't know. Isn't Phil kind of silly?
你说什么呢  菲尔是很棒的父亲
What are you talking about? Phil is a great father.
他和善
He's kind.
风趣
He's fun.
甚至莉莉都喜欢他
Even Lily likes him.
但他是不是太讨喜了
But is he too likeable?
严肃呢
Where's the gravitas?
他充满活力
He's full of energy.
他感情细腻
He's sensitive,
而且他从不会暴躁
and he never, ever gets grumpy.
好  那你何不现在就把乔交给这个超级老爸
Fine. Why don't you give Joe to Super Dad right now, then?
天啊  你真嫉妒了吗
Oh, my God, are you really jealous
就因为菲尔当可能是比你棒的老爸
because Phil might be a better father than you?
我知道这很蠢
I know it's stupid.
更别说这样的话乔还有了克莱尔
Not to mention the fact that Joe gets Claire in the deal.
她是个极出色的母亲
She's a fantastic mother.
经营公司  绝对的楷模
Runs a company, hell of a role model.
乔找不到比她更好母亲了
He could never do better than that for a mother.
其实吧  菲尔和克莱尔终于养大了孩子们
You know what, Phil and Claire have already raised their kids.
我觉得他们该享受旅行了
I think it's time for them to travel.
那里
There.
我的消失专用包原来就挂在那里
That's where my disappear bag was hanging!
歌洛莉亚都快把你电话打爆了
You have, like, a hundred missed calls from Gloria.
你们必须马上回来
You have to come back right now.
出什么事了吗
Is everything okay?
什么
What?
附近肯定有公交站台
There must be a bus stop nearby.
在那之前  表现得正常点
Until then, just act normal
就像我们没带四万美金
like we don't have $40,000 on us.
你为什么只半句小声说
Okay, why are you whispering only part of a sentence?
会引起注意的
That's going to attract attention.
真的吗
Really?
比你浑身大汗更引注意吗
More than you being covered in sweat?
你看着就像桑拿墙
Because you look like a sauna wall.
你说得对  我该怎么让自己别出汗呢
You're right. How do I make myself stop sweating?
我不知道
I don't know!
别哭  哭比出汗更糟
Oh, don't cry. Crying's worse than sweating.
瞧吧  我也哭了
Oh look, now I'm crying too!
或许我们笑着笑着就不哭了
Maybe we can smile our way out of this.
-菲尔  -怎么
- Phil? - Yeah?
亲爱的  快来  你爸在房车上晕倒了
Honey, come quick! Your dad passed out in the RV.
天啊
Oh, my God!
爸  你没事吧
Dad, are you okay?
没事  克莱尔刚不小心拿水管喷到我了
Yeah, Claire just accidentally sprayed me with a garden hose.
真的吗
Really?
克莱尔
Oh, Claire?
抱歉  卡住了
Sorry, stuck...
就像许多父子关系一样
like many father/son relationships.
这里看着很棒
So, uh, place looks great.
洛林把这里收拾一新
Yeah, Lorraine really spruced it up --
窗帘
curtains,
厕所装了铜护栏
brass safety rails over the privy.
那可真是救命的玩意儿
That was really a lifesaver.
她有次在90号公路上急刹车
She stopped short on the I-90 once.
我就像中国杂技演员一样翻了出去
I came rolling out of there like a Chinese acrobat.
洛林似乎很不错
Well, Lorraine seems good.
菲尔  你今天似乎有点不对劲
Hey, so Phil, uh, you seem a little off today.
我和洛林在一起  你不会觉得别扭吧
Me and Lorraine -- uh, that doesn't bother you, right?
不  不
No. No.
那就好  这事挺疯狂
Good. It's the craziest thing.
她当时再次介绍自己
She re-introduced herself,
我根本不记得她是我们的保姆
and, uh, I didn't even remember she was our babysitter.
真的吗
Really?
是啊  然后她约我出去
Yeah. Then she asked me out,
你也知道  约我的不多
and you know, I don't get a lot of offers,
我就想  "管他的"
so I thought, "What the heck?"
我猜也是
Sure. That's what I figured.
但我很高兴你过得愉快
But, uh, I'm just glad you're having fun.
我最好去把我这瓶子
Well, I better go fill this thing up
装满杰昂贵的威士忌了
with some of Jay's expensive Scotch.
其实  门似乎锁上了
Oh, actually, I think the door's locked.
没有  好得很
Oh, no, it's fine.
弗兰克  非常抱歉水管喷到你了
Well, Frank, I'm really sorry about that hose thing.
没什么
Oh, no hard feelings.
我衣服也该洗洗了
Shirt needed freshening anyway.
反正打从
I haven't washed it
上次我们停车下来跟火轮海拍照就没洗了
since we stopped to take pictures at Smokey-Top,
火轮海是犹他州历时最长的轮胎弃置场大火
Utah's longest, continuously burning tire fire.
我猜你也听到了  我完全没什么好担心
As I guess you heard, I had no reason to be worried.
他本来都没意识到洛林曾是我的保姆
He didn't even notice when Lorraine was my babysitter.
而且他们也不是太认真在谈恋爱
Plus, they're not even that serious.
我摸到了他口袋里有戒指盒
I felt a ring box in his pocket.
什么  不可能
What? No way.
真的
Yep.
世上没有别的东西是那个形状了
There's only one thing shaped like that.
才没有  那形状的东西多了
No, there isn't. There's a million things --
魔方  针线包
Rubik's Cube, sewing kit,
火轮海的纪念品轮胎钥匙圈
souvenir tire keychain from Smokey-Top.
我都想不出有什么东西不是那形状了
I can't think of anything that's not shaped like that.
我们就先假设一下我感觉对了
Let's assume for a moment that I am right
那真的是戒指盒
and that was a ring box.
我觉得挺值得探讨
Maybe it's worth exploring
为什么你爸爸续弦
why the idea of your dad remarrying
会让你这么惴惴不安
is setting you off like this.
或许也很值得探讨
Maybe it's worth exploring
为什么你这么享受把人搞崩溃
why you find so much joy in tearing people down.
在早年
In previous generations,
人们可是会说你们这种人是女巫
they accused people like that of being witches
朝你们泼水  如果尖叫就真是女巫
and threw water at them to see if they screamed.
好棒棒
Great.
女巫
Witch.
猎女巫时期有很多毫无科学根据的查女巫手法
我猜您就是普里契特先生吧
Ah, Mr. Pritchett, I presume.
你好  谢谢你辛苦跑这一趟
Hi. Thank you so much for coming.
我不太确定我有没有听对你名字
I'm not sure I caught your name.
-基夫斯·班克斯  -太好了
- Keifth Banks. - Yes.
随时为您...
At your --
米奇尔  抱歉打断你了
Mitchell, sorry to interrupt.
我不知道你在跟个普通工人聊天
I didn't know you were with a common worker.
万万没想到
Can it be?
卡梅隆·塔克
Cameron Tucker.
是的  不好意思  您是...
Yes. I'm sorry. You are...?
基夫斯
Keifth.
基夫斯  我好像不记得有认识...
Keifth. I-I don't believe I know --
不对  小卡  你不是跟我说过
No, C-Cam, didn't you tell me
你曾跟一个叫基夫斯的人在一起过吗
you once dated someone named Keifth?
对哦  基夫斯
Oh, yes. Keifth.
你当年是做什么的来着
What was it you did again?
我记得你戴着白手套  然后很多肢体动作
I remember you wore white gloves and -- and gestured a lot.
地铁站的默剧演出者吗
Subway mime?
我是马戏团的领导
I commanded a circus.
是的  现在我想起来了
Yes. Now I remember.
你还好吗
How have you been?
你现在干起送猪到府的行当了吗
I see you're in pig delivery now?
我是一位礼宾人员
I'm a concierge.
马戏团的行当这年头越来越艰难
The circus business has gotten rather difficult.
现在的人没有那种耐心
People today, they don't have the patience
去欣赏早年那种更优雅的演出了
for the more elegant pleasures of yesteryear --
比如看人把头放进狮子嘴里
men putting their heads into lion's mouths,
可怜的侏儒被从大炮里射出
unfortunate little people being shot from cannons.
真不敢相信  你们会在这种情况下重逢
I can't believe you-- you're meeting up again like this.
你们之间肯定有很多话想聊
You must have so much to catch up on
或很多事想处理吧
or -- or -- or work through.
我相信基夫斯比较想
Oh, well, I'm sure Keifth would rather
把东西送到之后就人间蒸发吧
just make the delivery and disappear.
就从这个开始处理
Start there.
说说手里的这问题
To the matter at hand.
要大换烤猪是比较困难的
The swap will be difficult.
幸好我对误导观众目光焦点颇有经验
Fortunately, I have had a bit of experience with misdirects --
只需要叫观众集中注意看着舞台中央
just tell the audience to keep your eyes on the center ring!
他们就不会发现舞台上方的空中飞人
They won't even notice the trapeze act
正在艰难地度过食物中毒反应较大的阶段
suffering through the more vivid stages of food poisoning.
真事  我当时也在场
That happened. I was there.
首先  我放出一只活孔雀
First, I will release a live peacock --
来自东方的异国珍兽  进后院
an exotic beauty of the Orient -- into the yard.
太魔幻
Magical.
然后我需要有能把它吸引进屋的东西
Then, I will need something to lure him inside
好吸引所有人的注意力
to draw the family's attention.
你们有西班牙安达卢西亚的榛果吗
Do you happen to have any Andalusian filberts?
没有
No.
那就用起司小饼干吧
Then Cheez-Its will do.
普通人在这时候都会呆住
Naturally, everyone will be transfixed.
这时趁他们不注意  我们就把猪给换了
And while they're distracted, we will swap out the pigs,
晚餐就起死回生  一切就能继续
the dinner will be saved, and the show will go on.
让我先偷看一眼后院
Just let me sneak a peek at the backyard.
再见啦
Goodbye.
乔
Hey, Joe,
什么东西有两头四脚还会飞
what has two heads, four legs, and can fly?
不知道
I don't know.
我们
Us. Aah!
这样很危险
This is dangerous!
玩心跳才知道自己还活着啊
That's how you know we're alive!
就像我在婚礼致辞时说的
It's like I said in my wedding toast --
你的新娘天不怕地不怕
that bride of yours is fearless.
对啊
Yeah.
而奇怪的是  今天早先我们去了游乐园
Funny thing is, we went to an amusement park earlier today
她却不敢去坐其中一个设施
and she was too scared to get on this one ride.
又或者她假装不敢
Or she pretended to be
这样我就不用承认自己有多怕坐那个了
so that I wouldn't have to admit how scared I was.
我有个感觉  她不是今天
I have a hunch that she's not the only one
唯一一个想保护我感受的人
who's trying to protect my feelings today.
儿啊  你讲话有点含糊不清啊
You seem to be rambling, son.
你早先跟克莱尔拥抱时
When you hugged Claire earlier,
她摸到你口袋里有戒指盒状物
she felt a ring box in your pocket.
什么  那才不是戒指盒
What? That wasn't a ring box.
那是...  我现在在哪里  我老糊涂了
It was...where am I? I'm so old and confused.
别演了
Stop.
我不会否认看到你跟洛林在一起
I'm not gonna say seeing you with Lorraine
没有任何别扭的感觉
wasn't a little bit weird for me.
的确是很疯狂的一件事啦
It was a crazy idea.
我要说的不是这个
That's not what I'm trying to say.
那头猪应该烤熟了吧
That pig's got to be ready, doesn't it?
爸  别这样
Dad, please.
儿啊  我们能不这样吗
Son, can we please not do this?
好吧
Fine.
咚咚咚
Knock, knock.
这还比较像话
That's more like it.
是谁在敲门啊
Who's there?
-你儿子  -哪位你儿子
- Your son. - Your son, who?
你那位不想你因为他而放弃
Your son who'd hate to think you threw away
自己幸福的机会来保护他感受的儿子
a shot at happiness just to protect his feelings.
给你  都在这  从我手里拿走它吧
Here it is. All here. Just take it from me.
这是我这辈子压力最大的一次
That's the most stress I've ever felt,
我可是曾在地底待过两周
and I spent two weeks underground
来做孤独有关的研究呢
as part of an isolation study.
好啦
Okay.
我们现在应该能把这弄完啦
So, I guess now we can finish this.
米奇  米奇  过来帮我们填完这个
Ay, Mitch. Mitch, come. Help us finish.
好的  好的  我们用快问快答来填完这些表
Okay. Okay. We got to lightning round these forms.
你们俩都想得太多了
You guys are overthinking this.
其实答案早就在每个人心里了
Everybody knows in their heart what they want.
大家只是都不好意思做出那决定
They just feel bad about making the decision.
那开始吧  你要选谁做你的遗嘱执行人  请作答
So, who will be the executor of your estate? Go.
你  好的
You. Aww. Okay.
你有什么想要捐给慈善机构的吗
Um, do you want to leave anything to charity?
有
Yes.
一成财产捐给我们去世时最拉风的慈善项目
10% to whatever is sexy at the time we die --
比如像孤儿什么的吧
like, um, orphans or whatever.
好的  好的  下一题那斯黛拉呢
Okay, okay, yeah. And what about Stella?
跟曼尼一人一半
Same as Manny.
不是  他是在问你斯黛拉该由谁来照顾
No, he's asking who's gonna take care of her,
不是问你打算留多少钱给一个杀人凶手
not how much money you're gonna leave to a murderer.
没证据啊
No proof of that.
好吧  感觉那事值得另外谈过
Okay, this seems like a whole sidebar,
我们一会再绕回来讨论这个吧
so we're gonna circle back to that.
下一个  你想要谁来做乔的法定监护人
Um, who do you want as Joe's legal guardian?
别  别去想  按直觉回答一个  好吗
No, no, don't think. Just answer, okay?
如果万一你们两个都遭遇了不幸
If something happens to both of you,
你最想要谁来照顾乔
who do you want to take care of Joe?
我啊  这还用说
Me, obviously.
曼尼  你还太小了
Ay, Manny, you're too young.
而且不久之后你马上就要开始自己新的生活了
Besides, you're about to start your new life soon.
是啊  你应该致力出去播种
Yeah, you should be out sowing your oats
或者致力织布吧
or just sewing.
反正你正好喜欢这个
That's something you like.
我不觉得这有什么大问题
I don't see what the big deal is.
我会雇个保姆  卖了房子  换到小点的公寓里
I'd hire a nanny, sell the house, downsize to a condo.
我在考虑正要蓬勃发展的艺术街区的复式楼
I'm thinking maybe a loft in an up-and-coming arts district.
的确  这些事可能会延迟我大学毕业的时间
Sure, it'll take me a bit longer to finish college,
但反正大学也是生命里最好的一段时光  不是吗
but aren't those the best years of life, anyway?
但最重要的是  他是我的弟弟
The main thing is, he's my brother.
我不会答应让除了我之外的人来把他养大
I'm not letting anybody else raise him.
曼尼  你太贴心了
Ay, Manny. You're so sweet.
难道我是唯一对他已经把
Am I the only one unsettled
这事计划如此透彻而感到不安的人吗
by how much he's thought about that already?
-我的天啊  快看  -什么鬼
-Oh, my God! Look! -What?
施放你的法术吧  大自然的万花筒
Cast your spell, nature's kaleidoscope!
为什么会有一只蓝色的火鸡出现在房子里
Why is there a blue turkey going into the house?
那是孔雀好吗
It's a peacock.
猛吃那一路的起司小饼干啊
It's really plowing through the Cheez-Its.
我们忘记塞苹果在新猪嘴里了
Oh, we forgot to put the apple the new pig's mouth.
这事儿先扔下吧
Oh, just leave it.
你解决所有问题的方式就是扔下吗
Now that's your answer to everything, isn't it?
你骂的对
I deserve that.
我是个傻子  居然以为能在你不提
I was a fool to think I could get through this
我当年如何离开的方式下  处理完这事
without you bringing up the way I left.
你伤透了我的心
Well, you broke my heart.
我并不是故意要伤害你  卡梅隆
I didn't mean to hurt you, Cameron.
我只是不得不去保护自己
I just had to protect myself.
当初我们刚认识的时候  你就仿佛
When we first met, you were just...
未经雕琢的璞玉
pure, raw potential.
你的密苏里腔调
Your Missouri twang.
不懂得怎么弄衬衫袖口的样子
The innocent way your shirt cuffs
显得你单纯又可爱
were no different than your sleeves.
只要你从你乡村的这茧中破蛹而出
Once you emerged from your country cocoon,
而我知道这是迟早的事情
I knew it was just a matter of time
你就会发现世界很大  然后就往天空飞去
before you realized you could do better and moved on.
但你连一声再见都没有说过
But you never even said goodbye.
这些年来 我一直觉得是我做得不够好
For all these years, I-I thought it was my fault.
不  不
Oh, no.
不是这样的
No.
我是一个懦夫
I was a coward.
我就这么跑了  然后加入了别的马戏团
I just ran away to join another circus.
我猜你可以这么说
I suppose you could say the --
你还没称霸的那"环"舞台  名为因果循"环"
the one ring you never mastered was the ring of life.
这吐槽有点狠  但所言在理
Well, that's kind of mean, but sure.
不过看看你们这么漂亮的房子
And look at your beautiful home.
你已经成长为了一个成功人士了
Oh, it's... You've blossomed into the success
我一直都相信你可以的
I always knew you'd be.
没错
Correct.
我很享受我们在一起的时光  卡梅隆
I did so enjoy our time together, Cameron.
你还记得我们在两个城市来回表演的那一周吗
Remember that split week between Lansing and Kalamazoo?
我的天  我怎么可能不记得
Oh, my gosh, how could I forget?
雨滴落在帐篷顶上
the rain dripping on the canvas.
马戏团宵禁之后  我偷溜进你的马车里
Me sneaking into your wagon after curfew.
我想那应该是你第一次看见我的大...
I believe that was the first time you saw me...
礼帽没戴在头上的时候
without my top hat.
好吧
Okay.
好了  疗伤完毕
Well, wounds healed,
开始新的篇章  您可以放心走了
whole new perspective, off you go.
再见  卡梅隆
Goodbye, Cameron.
再见  基夫斯
Goodbye, Keifth.
是你啊  亲爱的
Oh, hey, honey.
这是要做什么
I, uh... Whatcha doing?
他这么紧张的样子看起来好可爱
Oh, I think it's cute how scared he is.
对啊  但他去做了
Yeah, but he's doing it.
我愿意
Yes.
一个不怕活得刺激点儿的邓菲家男人
There's one Dunphy who's not afraid to live dangerously.
我说  克莱尔
Hey, Claire?
它们还有两个小时才打烊
They're open for two more hours.
一定会平安无事的
Everything's gonna be okay.
2017!
将会成为很棒...
It's gonna be a great yea--
菲尔
Phil?
小卡  这也太好吃了
Cam, this is so delicious.
你知道的  继上一个感恩节之后
Well, you know, after Thanksgiving,
我只是庆幸这次一切都没有出差错
I'm just happy nothing went wrong.
我好爱这个调料
I love this seasoning.
那个坚果口感是哪来的
What gives it that nutty taste?
可能就是坚果啊  亲爱的
It might be nuts, sweetheart.
不可能  他不会放坚果进来的
Oh, no, he wouldn't put nuts in it.
他知道我对坚果过敏
He knows I'm allergic.
借过一下
Excuse me.
我回来了  回来啦
Hi. Hi.
云霄飞车感觉怎么样
Hey, how was the ride?
太棒了  但菲尔晕过去了
Amazing. Phil fainted.
克莱尔
Claire.
别装了  他们肯定会发现的
Oh, come on, they were gonna find out.
因为我绝不可能花了15块钱买了这张照片
I'm not spending $15 on this picture
却忍住不给大家看
and not show it to everyone.
我可能需要你把嘴里的东西吐在这张餐巾上
I'm just gonna need you to spit into this napkin.
肾上腺素针马上送到
Epipen is on the way
这卡你留着吧
Just keep the card
是不是超赞
Is that amazing?